Guide to the Richard Erdoes Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Subject Files, 1951-1998; Series VI; 6.26; (15 boxes)
  - People
    - Crow Dog, Leonard
      - "Prison Letters", 1971-1981, undated (Box 174, Folder 824)
        Includes correspondence to and from Erdoes about Crow Dog's imprisonment. Correspondents include Mary Brave Bird and other supporters of Crow Dog
      - Clippings, 1972-1988, undated (Box 174, Folder 825)
      - Native American Church, [after 1972, undated] (Box 174, Folder 826)
      - "Prison", 1973-1979, undated (Box 175, Folder 827-829)
        Consists of materials related to Crow Dog's incarceration, including pleas for furloughs and amnesty
      - "Peyote, Texas - Pharmacy Permit", [after 1973 November 16] (Box 175, Folder 830)
      - United States of America vs. Leonard Crow Dog trial transcript (photocopy), 1975 November 20 (Box 175, Folder 831)
      - "Beck - McCloskey Trial", 1975-1976 (Box 175, Folder 832)
      - "Crow Dog Legal", 1975-1981 (Box 175, Folder 833-834)
      - Letters of support during and after 1974 trial (photocopies), 1975-1976, undated (Box 175, Folder 835)
      - "Resolution on Native American Concerns", 1976 March 4 (Box 175, Folder 836)
      - "Crow Dog, Richmond Va.", [after 1976 April] (Box 175, Folder 837)
      - "Crow Dog Released", [circa 1976 June] (Box 175, Folder 838)
      - "Crow Dog's Home Destroyed", [after 1976 November] (Box 175, Folder 839)
      - Connecticut Friends of Indians. "Native American Day" mailer, 1976 (Box 175, Folder 840)
      - Petition (photocopy), [circa 1976] (Box 175, Folder 841)
      - Sanford Jay Rosen, Esq. Memorandum in Support of Leonard Emmanuel Crow Dog's Application for Presidential Amnesty, 1977 August (Box 175, Folder 842)
      - "Sacred Objects", [circa 1970s-1980s] (Box 175, Folder 843)
      - "Article on His Youth", undated (Box 176, Folder 844)
      - "Basis of Indian Religion", undated (Box 176, Folder 845)
      - Crow Dog film scripts, undated (Box 176, Folder 846-848)
      - "Crow Dog For [Tribal] Chairman", undated (Box 176, Folder 849)
      - "Duties of a Spiritual Leader", undated (Box 176, Folder 850)
      - "Inner Feelings Talk", undated (Box 176, Folder 851)
      - "J'accuse!", undated (Box 176, Folder 852)
      - "Mary [Brave Bird] on Pfersick Case", undated (Box 176, Folder 853)
      - "William McCloskey Letter", undated (Box 176, Folder 854)
      - Transcripts
        - "Arizona Peyote Trials and Incidents", undated (Box 176, Folder 855)
        - "Barry Gray Interview.", undated (Box 176, Folder 856)
        - Bloodclot Boy, two accounts of We Ota Wic hasha legend, 1969, 1980 (Box 176, Folder 857)
        - "Calf Pipe", 1971, undated (Box 176, Folder 858)
        - "Ceremonies", 1971 November 16, undated (Box 176, Folder 859)
        - "Crow Dog Ann Arbor Interview", [after 1975 October 10] (Box 176, Folder 860)
        - "Crow Dog, L. Washington, D.C.", 1977 April 25 (Box 176, Folder 861)
        - "Crow Dog on Marriage", 1971 November 10 (Box 176, Folder 862)
        - "Crow Dog - [Paul] Armstrong", undated (Box 176, Folder 863)
        - "Crow Dog, Peyote, John C. D., Sister, Medicine Men", undated (Box 176, Folder 864)
        - "Crow Dog Reservation Condition", undated (Box 176, Folder 865)
        - "Crow Dog Tape: Morning Star, Peyote, Iktomi, Coming of Wasichun", undated (Box 176, Folder 866)
        - "Crow Dog Tape KKK: Horse Dance, Peyote, Witch Doctor...", undated (Box 176, Folder 867)
        - "Crow Dog Unmarked Tape: AIM, Peyote, Family History...", undated (Box 176, Folder 868)
        - "Crow Dog Visits Penitentiaries", undated (Box 176, Folder 869)
        - "Crow Dog WBAI Interview", [after 1973 July 12] (Box 176, Folder 870)
        - "Drum - Sacred Hoop", 1971 Nov 21 (Box 177, Folder 871)
        - "Hanbleceya", 1970, undated (Box 177, Folder 872)
        - "Horse Dance", undated (Box 177, Folder 873)
        - "L. Crow Dog / Prison / Henry's Life / Alcatraz: Richard Oaks", undated (Box 177, Folder 874)
        - "L. Dog: Begin[n]ing and Introduction of Spiritual Life", 1976 January 20 (Box 177, Folder 875)
        - "Leonard", 1973 May 28, undated (Box 177, Folder 876)
        - "Leonard Crow Dog Unmarked Tape", undated (Box 177, Folder 877)
        - "Leonard / Peyote", 1977 April 19 (Box 177, Folder 878)
        - "Leonard / Prison", 1977 April 13 (Box 177, Folder 879)
        - "Medicine Talk", undated (Box 177, Folder 880)
        - "Medicine Woman: Bessie Good Road", 1971 November 10 (Box 177, Folder 881)
        - "My Crow Dog Interview - In Jail, Rapid City, 1975/76", 1975-1976 (Box 177, Folder 882)
        - "Peyote - Leonard Youth - Brother's Story", undated (Box 177, Folder 883)
        - "Peyote, Longhand", 1971-1977, undated (Box 177, Folder 884-885)
        - "Sun Creation", 1981 March 18 (Box 177, Folder 886)
        - "Sundance - Ghost Dance - Longhand", 1971 November 19 (Box 177, Folder 887)
        - "Sweat Lodge", 1975-1976, undated (Box 177, Folder 888)
        - "Talk with Crowdog ", 1974 November 15 (Box 177, Folder 889)
        - "Tape #9: Yuwipi Ceremony at Crow Dog's...", 1970 Oct 3 (Box 177, Folder 890)
        - Tape CCC, 1981 (Box 177, Folder 891)
        - Tape DDD, 1981 (Box 177, Folder 892)
        - Tape EEE, 1981 Mar 21 (Box 177, Folder 893)
        - "Unmarked Tape 1", undated (Box 177, Folder 894)
        - "Vision, Longhand", undated (Box 177, Folder 895)
        - "Yuwipi Longhand", undated (Box 177, Folder 896)
        - Unfiled material, [circa 1970s-1980s] (Box 177, Folder 897)
    - Dacajeweiah (John Hill), undated (Box 178, Folder 898)
    - Deere, Phillip, 1975, undated (Box 178, Folder 899)
    - Deloria, Vine, 1973 (Box 178, Folder 900)
    - Desersa, Byron, [1975?] (Box 178, Folder 901)
    - Durham, Douglas, 1975-1976, undated (Box 178, Folder 902)
    - Durham, Jimmie, undated (Box 178, Folder 903)
    - Fast Horse, Nick, 1973 (Box 178, Folder 904)
    - Fool Bull, Richard, 1968, undated (Box 178, Folder 905-906)
    - Fool's Crow, Frank, undated (Box 178, Folder 907)
    - Goings, Warfield Milo, [1973] (Box 178, Folder 908)
    - Grant, Dorothy. Haida designer, 1989-1995 (Box 178, Folder 909)
    - Harjo, Suzan Shown, 1992, undated (Box 178, Folder 910)
    - Harris, La Donna, 1970 (Box 178, Folder 911)
    - Hayes, Ira, undated (Box 178, Folder 912)
    - Highwater, Jamake, 1955-1984, undated (Box 178, Folder 913)
    - Hladky, Alex, undated (Box 178, Folder 914)
    - Horn, Kahn-Tineta, 1971 February 23 (Box 178, Folder 915)
    - Hyde, Douglas
      See: "Indian Artists"
    - Janklow, Bill, 1996, undated (Box 178, Folder 916)
    - Josephy Jr., Alvin M., 1971-1975 (Box 178, Folder 917)
    - Keams, Leroy, 1978-1979, undated (Box 178, Folder 918)
    - Kimball, Yeffe, 1978, undated (Box 178, Folder 919)
    - Lame Deer, undated (Box 178, Folder 920)
    - Lame Deer, Archie Fire, 1983-1994 (Box 178, Folder 921)
    - Lame Deer, John Fire, 1970-1978, undated (Box 178, Folder 922-924)
    - Little Brave, Norman, 1969-1970, undated (Box 178, Folder 925)
    - Little Dog, Maggie Six Shooter, 1970 Feburary 7 (Box 178, Folder 926)
    - Little Horn, Roger and Annette, 1972, undated (Box 178, Folder 927)
    - Littlefeather, Sacheen, 1990-1991, undated (Box 178, Folder 928)
    - Lyons, Oren, undated (Box 178, Folder 929)
    - Marshall, Dick, 1978, undated (Box 178, Folder 930)
    - Matthiessen, Peter, 1983 March 6 (Box 178, Folder 931)
    - Means, Russell, 1971-1992, undated (Box 179, Folder 932)
    - Mills, Sid, 1972 June 7 (Box 179, Folder 933)
    - Momaday, N. Scott, 1992 (Box 179, Folder 934)
    - Monture, Joel, 1982, undated (Box 179, Folder 935)
    - Naranjo, Michael, 1975 June (Box 179, Folder 936)
    - Niese, Henry, undated (Box 179, Folder 937)
    - Olguin, Rudi, 1991-1993, undated (Box 179, Folder 938)
    - One Star, Alex, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 939)
    - Oohosis, 1971 October 16, undated (Box 179, Folder 940-941)
    - Petite, Ron, 1978 (Box 179, Folder 942)
    - Plenty Horses, undated (Box 179, Folder 943)
    - Poor Thunder, Joe, undated (Box 179, Folder 944)
    - Primeaux, Francis, 1983 (Box 179, Folder 945)
    - Reagan, Harley Swiftdeer, undated (Box 179, Folder 946)
    - Red Bear, Albert, undated (Box 179, Folder 947)
    - Red Bear, Christine
      See: Brave Bird, Barbara
    - Reno, Marcus Alfred, 1967 May 4 (Box 179, Folder 948)
    - Rough Surface, Candace, 1996 February 20 (Box 179, Folder 949)
    - Roy, Jerry, 1976 (Box 179, Folder 950)
    - Sainte-Marie, Buffy, 1987, undated (Box 179, Folder 951)
    - Scholder, Fritz
    - Shano, John, undated (Box 179, Folder 952)
    - Shenandoah, Leon, 1996 August (Box 179, Folder 953)
    - Thorpe, Jim, 1972, undated (Box 179, Folder 954)
    - Westerman, Floyd, 1974 (Box 179, Folder 955)
    - Wilson, Dick, 1972-1975, undated (Box 179, Folder 956)
    - Yellow Hand, Lance Sands, undated (Box 179, Folder 957)
    - Young Bear, Severt, 1994, undated (Box 179, Folder 958)
    - Zephier, Mitchell, 1981-1982, undated (Box 179, Folder 959)
    - Unidentified transcripts, undated (Box 179, Folder 960)
  - Other Subjects
    - "1868 Treaty" [Treaty of Fort Laramie], 1973-1974, undated (Box 180, Folder 961)
    - "1971 Sundance", 1971 July-August (Box 180, Folder 962)
      Erdoes's first-hand account of a Sun Dance ceremony
    - "1971 Sundance Arrest", 1971 July 19 (Box 180, Folder 963)
    - Alcatraz Island (Calif.), Indian occupation, 1969-1973, undated (Box 180, Folder 964)
    - American Indian Community House (New York, N.Y.), undated (Box 180, Folder 965)
    - American Indian Movement
      - Anti-alcoholism, undated (Box 180, Folder 966)
      - Cedar Rapids (Iowa) trial and camp, 1975, undated (Box 180, Folder 967)
      - Colorado State University anthropology protest, 1971, undated (Box 180, Folder 968)
      - "FBI atrocities", 1973-1976, undated (Box 180, Folder 969)
      - General clippings, 1971-1973, undated (Box 180, Folder 970)
      - National convention, 1973 July 27 (Box 180, Folder 971)
      - Other papers, 1973, undated (Box 180, Folder 972)
      - Press releases, 1973-1975 (Box 180, Folder 973)
      - United States Senate investigation, 1976, undated (Box 180, Folder 974)
        See also: Indian activism
    - "Bertrand Russel Tribunal" [Russell Tribunals], [circa 1980], undated (Box 180, Folder 975)
    - "Big Mountain" [Big Mountain (Ariz.)], 1977-1996, undated (Box 180, Folder 976)
    - Black Hills Alliance of South Dakota, 1979-1980, undated (Box 180, Folder 977)
    - Black Hills (S.D. and Wyo.), 1982, undated (Box 180, Folder 978)
    - Camp Yellow Thunder (S.D.), 1982, undated (Box 180, Folder 979)
    - "Cankpe Opi - Govt. Hearings" [Wounded Knee - Govt. Hearings], 1973 (Box 180, Folder 980)
    - Ceder Rapids Case, clippings (photocopies), [circa 1975] (Box 180, Folder 981)
    - Center for Constitutional Rights (New York, N.Y.), 1976-1978 (Box 180, Folder 982)
    - Chippewa treaty rights, undated (Box 180, Folder 983)
    - City of Refuge Facilities, undated (Box 180, Folder 984)
    - Crowdogs' Indian Way School, undated (Box 180, Folder 985)
    - Custer (S.D.), 1973, undated (Box 180, Folder 986)
    - "Dancing with Garbage on Sioux Land," Baltimore Sun clipping, 1991 February 26 (Box 180, Folder 987)
    - "Desecration - Indian Cemetaries", 1971-1996, undated (Box 180, Folder 988)
    - "Dog Feast", undated (Box 180, Folder 989)
    - "Dog Soldiers, 1976" (Box 180, Folder 990)
    - "Eagle Dance", undated (Box 181, Folder 991)
    - "Elections at Pine Ridge", 1973, undated (Box 181, Folder 992)
    - "Ellis Island" [Attempted occupation], 1970 March 17, undated (Box 181, Folder 993)
    - "Elk Medicine - Deer Medicine", 1968, undated (Box 181, Folder 994)
    - "Fake Gurus", undated (Box 181, Folder 995)
      Includes untitled corrected typescript, 4 p.
    - "Feather Cases", 1983 (Box 181, Folder 996)
    - Fellowship of Reconciliation (New York), undated (Box 181, Folder 997)
    - "Fishing Rights", 1968-1990, undated (Box 181, Folder 998)
    - "Flesh Offerings", undated (Box 181, Folder 999)
    - "Gaming", 1993 December 22 (Box 181, Folder 1000)
    - "Ganienke" [Mohawk occupation of Adirondacks State Park land], 1974, undated (Box 181, Folder 1001)
    - "General - Indian", 1959-1992, undated (Box 181, Folder 1002)
    - "Geneva" [UN Conference on Discrimination against Indigenous Peoples of the Americas], 1977 December (Box 181, Folder 1003)
    - "Ghost Dance", [circa 1970s-1980s] (Box 181, Folder 1004)
    - "Give Away", undated (Box 181, Folder 1005)
    - "Grass Mountain - Peyote - Certificate", [after 1977] (Box 181, Folder 1006)
    - "Health Care and Medicine Man", 1971, 1972 (Box 181, Folder 1007)
    - "Herbs", undated (Box 181, Folder 1008)
    - "Heyoka", 1970 October 14, undated (Box 181, Folder 1009)
    - "Hopi", 1967-1982, undated (Box 181, Folder 1010)
    - Indian activism, 1968-1972, undated (Box 182, Folder 1011)
    - Indians, art, 1988, undated (Box 182, Folder 1012)
    - "Indian Artists", 1974-1992 (Box 182, Folder 1013)
    - "Indian Dates", undated (Box 182, Folder 1014)
    - "Indian Education", 1973-1995, undated (Box 182, Folder 1015-1016)
    - "Indian Film", 1986-1991, undated (Box 182, Folder 1017)
    - "Indian Inmates", 1974-1996, undated (Box 182, Folder 1018)
    - "Indian International Treaty Council" [International Indian Treaty Council], 1975-1990, undated (Box 182, Folder 1019-1020)
    - "Indian Letters - Miscellaneous", 1971-1977, undated (Box 182, Folder 1021)
    - "Indian Prehistory", 1969-1993, undated (Box 182, Folder 1022)
    - "Indian Rights - Misc. Articles, Etc.", 1962-1996, undated (Box 182, Folder 1023-1024)
    - Indians, Sioux, 1991, undated (Box 182, Folder 1025)
    - Indians, other clippings, 1968-1979, undated (Box 182, Folder 1026)
    - "Inipi", undated (Box 182, Folder 1027)
    - Jim Thorpe Run, 1984 (Box 183, Folder 1028)
    - "John Fire vs. Janklow" [John Fire's suit against Winner, South Dakota], [1971?] (Box 183, Folder 1029)
    - "Lakota Dictionary", undated (Box 183, Folder 1030-1032)
    - "Longest Walk" [1978 Longest Walk, 1994 Walk for Justice], 1978, 1994, undated (Box 183, Folder 1033)
    - "A Man Called Horse", [1970] (Box 183, Folder 1034)
      Typescript introduction to film, signed by Sanford Howard (producer), accompanied by list of credits
    - "Matthiessen 'Outside', Peltier Article", 1995 October (Box 183, Folder 1035)
      Matthiessen, Peter. "Mean Spirit: Are Peltier's supporters-- or his attackers-- the true "merchants of myth?". Outside (magazine) clipping
    - "Mayflower" [AIM occupation of Plymouth Rock and Mayflower II], 1970, undated (Box 183, Folder 1036)
    - "Meeting at Hairshirt 1981" (Box 183, Folder 1037)
    - "Menominee" [Menominee Warrior Society occupation of Alexian Brothers Novitiate, Gresham, Wisconsin], 1975-1976 (Box 183, Folder 1038)
    - "Milwaukee Coast Guard Sta" [AIM seizure of Milwaukee Coast Guard station], [1972] (Box 183, Folder 1039)
    - "Mohawk", 1972, undated (Box 183, Folder 1040)
    - "Mt. Rushmore Occupation 1970/1", [1970-1971] (Box 183, Folder 1041)
    - "Museum Info", 1982-1991, undated (Box 183, Folder 1042)
    - "Names of Goon Victims" [List of AIM members and supporters murdered on the Pine Ridge Reservation, 1972-76], [1976] (Box 183, Folder 1043)
    - "Navajo Peyote Report", [after 1940] (Box 183, Folder 1044)
    - Native American Church, undated (Box 183, Folder 1045)
    - "New Indian Wars", 1994 (Box 183, Folder 1046)
    - "Nuclear Waste", 1979-1998 (Box 183, Folder 1047)
    - "Nixon's Message" ["Excerpts from Nixon's Message on Indian Affairs," New York Times clipping], 1970 July 9 (Box 183, Folder 1048)
    - "On Religion" [AIM demonstration at 1974 Mormon general conference] (Box 183, Folder 1049)
    - "Peltier - Misc." [Leonard Peltier Defense Committee and other support groups], 1990-1991, undated (Box 183, Folder 1050)
    - "Peltier - Nantinki Rose" [Native American Sundancers Vigil for Justice], 1991, undated (Box 183, Folder 1051)
    - "Peyote", 1971-1974, undated (Box 184, Folder 1052-1053)
    - "Peyote - 'An Insidious Evil'", undated (Box 184, Folder 1054)
    - "Peyote and the Indian - D'Arcy McNickle", undated (Box 184, Folder 1055)
    - "Peyote Letter", undated (Box 184, Folder 1056)
    - "Peyote Miscellaneous", 1963 January (Box 184, Folder 1057)
    - "Peyote Pan-Indianism", undated (Box 184, Folder 1058)
    - "Peyote - Printed Report", [after 1961 April 18] (Box 184, Folder 1059)
    - "Peyote Songs - Texts - Words", undated (Box 184, Folder 1060)
    - "Peyote Statute 1924", undated (Box 184, Folder 1061)
    - "Pine Ridge - Misc.", 1972, undated (Box 184, Folder 1062)
    - "Plant Poisoning", undated (Box 184, Folder 1063)
    - "Political Prisoners - AIM", 1977-1995, undated (Box 184, Folder 1064)
    - "Powwows, Pageants, Etc.", 1968-1995, undated (Box 184, Folder 1065)
    - "Purification Ceremonies", undated (Box 184, Folder 1066)
    - "Rapid City Demonstration 1973", 1972-1973, undated (Box 184, Folder 1067)
    - "Religious Freedom Bill", undated (Box 184, Folder 1068)
    - "Religious Suppression", undated (Box 184, Folder 1069)
      Includes Erdoes's manuscript notes with corrections
    - "Repression - Bringing Vietnam Home; Cable Splicer; Garden Plot", 1975, undated (Box 184, Folder 1070)
    - "Rockie: Peace & Dignity" [ Peace And Dignity Journeys, newsletter, ed. Rocky Rodriguez], [1997] (Box 184, Folder 1071)
    - "Rosebud - Misc." [Rosebud Indian Reservation (S. D.)], 1970, undated (Box 184, Folder 1072)
    - "Sacred Hoop", undated (Box 184, Folder 1073)
    - "Sacred Lands", 1981 December (Box 184, Folder 1074)
    - "St. Francis Mission", undated (Box 184, Folder 1075)
    - "Shoot Out at Oglala", 1975-1992, undated (Box 184, Folder 1076)
    - "Sioux Falls Trial", 1974-1979, undated (Box 185, Folder 1077)
    - "Sioux"
      Materials in this file were received in a large metal box that Erdoes had labeled with the word, "Sioux." Not all of the materials are related to the Lakota, Dakota, or Nakota peoples, but the materials have been kept together under this heading and ordered by format to reflect Erdoes's original arrangement of materials.
      - Brochures, 1966-1971, undated (Box 185, Folder 1078)
      - Clippings, 1954-1976, undated (Box 185, Folder 1079-1080)
      - Maps, undated (Box 185, Folder 1081)
      - Printed materials and ephemera, 1973, undated (Box 185, Folder 1082)
      - Programs, 1970, 1974 (Box 185, Folder 1083)
      - Publications, 1951-1972, undated (Box 185, Folder 1084-1085)
    - "Sioux Legal - Suit Against Wilson" [Wounded Knee Legal Defense/Offense Committee, et. al. vs. Dick Wilson, et. al., 1973. Copy of complaint] (Box 185, Folder 1086)
    - Sioux National Treaty Council, [after 1968] (Box 185, Folder 1087)
    - Skyhorse-Mohawk trial, 1976-1978 (Box 185, Folder 1088)
      Includes photocopies of correspondence related to the trial, newspaper clippings, and a subpeona from the Superior Court of California for Richard Erdoes to testify
    - "Soul Keeping", undated (Box 185, Folder 1089)
    - "Sovereignty", 1976-1978 (Box 185, Folder 1090)
    - "Spirituality", 1973-1992 (Box 185, Folder 1091)
    - "Spiritual - Misc.", 1990-1991, undated (Box 185, Folder 1092)
    - "Stereotypes: The White Indians", 1976 (Box 185, Folder 1093)
    - "Stomp Them Case, Eda Gordon" [Violence against Wounded Knee Legal Defense/Offense Committee, 1975], undated (Box 185, Folder 1094)
    - "Sun Dance", 1971-1981, undated (Box 185, Folder 1095)
    - "Thunder-Horse Ranch" [Mary Elizabeth Thunder], 1991-1992, undated (Box 185, Folder 1096)
    - "Trail of Broken Treaties / Take-over Indian Affairs Building" [Occupation of Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1972], 1972-1973, undated (Box 185, Folder 1097)
    - "Trail of Broken Treaties / Take-over ..." Clippings, 1972-1975, undated (Box 186, Folder 1098-1100)
    - "Travels Through America, 1766-1768", undated (Box 186, Folder 1101)
    - "Tribal Govt.: Justice, Law, Police", 1972, undated (Box 186, Folder 1102)
    - "Tribunal Hearing" [First American Indian International Tribunal, 1982], 1982, undated (Box 186, Folder 1103)
    - "Trouble at Pine Ridge and Paradise", 1973-1976, undated (Box 186, Folder 1104)
    - "Tukak Inuit", undated (Box 186, Folder 1105)
    - "Uranium, etc.", 1979-1980, undated (Box 186, Folder 1106)
    - "Wagner Plant", 1975 (Box 186, Folder 1107)
    - Water Contamination by the United States Government, 1980 (Box 186, Folder 1108)
    - "White Buffalo", 1994 (Box 186, Folder 1109)
    - "White Policy Proposal", undated (Box 186, Folder 1110)
    - "Witch Doctor", undated (Box 186, Folder 1111)
    - "Women", undated (Box 186, Folder 1112)
    - "Women - Isnati", undated (Box 186, Folder 1113)
    - "Wounded Knee, 1890", 1973-1975, undated (Box 186, Folder 1114)
    - Wounded Knee Occupation, 1973
      - Interviews and Personal Accounts
        - Bellecourt, Clyde, undated (Box 186, Folder 1115)
        - Benton-Benai, Eddie, undated (Box 186, Folder 1116)
        - Crow Dog, Leonard, [1973], undated (Box 186, Folder 1117-1118)
        - Griffin, Cyril, 1991, undated (Box 186, Folder 1119-1120)
        - Kelly, Pat, undated (Box 186, Folder 1121)
        - Lamont, Agnes, undated (Box 186, Folder 1122)
        - Lamont, Lawrence "Buddy", 1973, undated (Box 186, Folder 1123)
          Interviews and clippings about Lamont, including transcript of interview with Verna Steele
        - Little Wolf, Manny, undated (Box 187, Folder 1124)
        - Luck, Owen, undated (Box 187, Folder 1125)
        - Red Bear, Albert, undated (Box 187, Folder 1126)
        - Running, Diane, undated (Box 187, Folder 1127)
        - Four unidentified accounts, undated (Box 187, Folder 1128-1131)
        - "Quotes", 1973, undated (Box 187, Folder 1132)
      - Reports and Publications
        - "Observing at Wounded Knee", 1973 March 11-18 (Box 187, Folder 1133)
          Typescript photocopy report compiled by Julie Latane, Bidge McKay and Jim Schrag for the Fellowship of Reconciliation
        - Wounded Knee National Communications Center. Bulletin No. 4, 1973 April 4 (Box 187, Folder 1134)
        - "Periodicals on Wounded Knee", 1973-1979, undated (Box 187, Folder 1135)
          File includes single issues of New Times, Wounded Knee News, The Minnesota Leader, and publications of the Native American Solidarity Committee and the Madison Supporters of Wounded Knee
        - Rundbrief. Indianer Heute 16/17, 1974 (Box 187, Folder 1136)
      - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings
        - "Wounded Knee - 1st Days", 1973 March (Box 187, Folder 1137)
        - "Wounded Knee - Middle Period", 1973 March - April, undated (Box 187, Folder 1138-1139)
        - "Wounded Knee - End", 1973-1975, undated (Box 187, Folder 1140)
        - "Wounded Knee - Aftermath", 1973, undated (Box 187, Folder 1141)
        - "Wounded Knee Article[s]", 1973-1975, undated (Box 187, Folder 1142)
        - "Wounded Knee Residents", 1973 March-May, undated (Box 188, Folder 1143)
        - "Wounded Knee Negotiations", 1973 April-May, undated (Box 188, Folder 1144)
        - "Akwesasne Notes on Wounded Knee", 1973 April, 1973 June (Box 188, Folder 1145)
          Includes partial sheet of Wounded Knee memorial stamps produced by Akwesasne Notes
        - "Clearwater, [Frank]", 1973 April, undated (Box 188, Folder 1146)
        - "Wounded Knee German Report", 1973 May 4, undated (Box 188, Folder 1147)
          Accompanied by 1 page photocopy of 1973 Wounded Knee Seed, a supplement to the Shannon County News (South Dakota)
        - "Associated Press Photographer Leaks to FBI", [1974] (Box 188, Folder 1148)
        - "Women's Trials", [1974?] (Box 188, Folder 1149)
        - "Army and FBI Involvement at Wounded Knee", 1974-1975 (Box 188, Folder 1150)